Sorry, Santa.
Perdona, Santa.
(CRASHING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
En episodios anteriores
Nathaniel? What are you doin', buddy? Hey, is everything okay?
¿Nathaniel? ¿Qué haces, campeón? ¿Va todo bien?
No pasa nada si no puedes venir en Navidad.
Hey. You know I'm gonna be there, like I said.
Ya os dije que iría, ¿o no?
So Ronin is dead, and the person who killed him is dead.
Así que Ronin está muerto y la persona que lo mató también.
That's convenient. How do you know this?
Qué oportuno todo. ¿Cómo lo sabes?
'Cause I was there.
Porque estuve allí.
MAN: Up next, we have an artifact
A continuación, un artefacto
recovered from the wreckage of the Avengers compound.
recuperado de los escombros de la base de los Vengadores.
MAN: The lots.
El reloj.
REPORTER: New York socialite Armand Duquesne was found dead in his home last night.
Duquesne, miembro de la alta sociedad,
This is Detective Caudie of the New York Police Department.
fue hallado muerto anoche en su casa.
Ms. Bishop, can you come down to the station for a quick chat?
Inspector Carlov, del Departamento de Policía de Nueva York.
¿Podría pasarse un momento por comisaría?
How'd you say Armand was killed?
¿Cómo dices que mataron a Armand?
Stabbed with a sword. BARTON: See if there's anything on Kazi.
Con una espada.
Mira a ver si aparece Kazi.
KATE: Okay, what's this company, Sloan Limited? Kazi is an employee?
Vale, ¿qué empresa es esta? ¿Sloan Limited? ¿Kazi trabaja ahí?
Let me see what I can pull up on Jack.
A ver qué encontramos de Jack.
And I've just been locked out.
Se ha bloqueado.
JACK: Don't move.
No te muevas.
Stay exactly where you are.
No des ni un paso más.
Jack, no!
Jack, ¡no!
What the hell is going on?
¿Qué pasa aquí?
And why is there an Avenger in my dining room?
¿Y qué hace un vengador en mi comedor?
Hi.
Hola.
Oh, my God. You're... You're Archer.
Madre mía. Eres... el arquero.
-Hawkeye. -Clint.
-Ojo de Halcón. -Clint.
-It's the branding issue, I'm telling you. -Yeah, sure.
-No te vendes bien, te lo tengo dicho. -Vale.
(CHUCKLES)
Ojo de Halcón
Hawkeye and I are working on a case, and we needed to use the bathroom.
Ojo de Halcón y yo estamos trabajando en un caso y necesitábamos ir al baño.
He did. So, we were by the house, we dropped in. No big deal.
Bueno, él. Y como pasábamos por aquí, hemos entrado. Ya está.
-Working on a case together? -How terrific.
-¿Estáis trabajando en un caso? -Cómo mola.
He's my partner.
Es mi socio.
We're not partners.
No somos socios.
Well, we're friends-slash-partners.
Bueno, somos amigos/socios.
I wouldn't really describe us as friends. (CELL PHONE CHIMES)
No diría que somos amigos.
Someone used my laptop to sign onto my work account ten minutes ago.
Alguien ha usado mi portátil para acceder a mi cuenta hace diez minutos.
Any thoughts, Kate?
¿Tienes idea de quién, Kate?
Hawkeye?
¿Ojo de Halcón?
You'll never get anything outta him. See, CB-One has trouble opening up. Nobody calls me CB-One.
Este no suelta prenda. C. B. tiene problemas de comunicación.
I'm just tryin' it out for a second.
Nadie me llama C. B.
Solo probaba para ver qué tal.
Probably some early childhood thing. He thinks he doesn't tell me much,
Será por algún trauma infantil. Se cree que no me cuenta mucho,
-but he ends up telling me all of it. -I tell her nothing.
-pero lo tengo calado. -No le cuento nada.
I think it's 'cause I'm generally pretty chill.
Creo que es porque soy una tía bastante tranqui.
I'm not like, "Oh, my God, Hawkeye!" (CHUCKLES)
No en plan: "Qué fuerte, Ojo de Halcón".
Definitely not chill.
De todo menos tranqui.
By the way, thank you... for saving the world.
Por cierto, gracias por salvar el mundo.
Don't mention it.
No hay de qué.
I would like my daughter to start telling me the truth.
Me gustaría que mi hija empezara a decirme la verdad.
I logged into your account because I needed information
Me he metido en tu cuenta porque necesitaba información
on an actual case with actual people who are in actual danger.
para un caso real con personas reales en peligro real.
So, Kate is helping you with an Avengers-level threat?
¿Kate te está ayudando con una amenaza de nivel Vengadores?
Well, not exactly.
Bueno, no exactamente.
But you are working together?
Pero sí estáis trabajando juntos.
Yes. Sounds weird, 'cause it is.
Sí. Suena raro porque es raro.
Okay.
Vale.
Well, I guess I'm just gonna have to trust everyone at this table to do what's right.
Pues tendré que confiar en que todos los aquí presentes hagamos lo correcto.
BARTON: Hmm.
Cool. It was great bumpin' into you guys.
Vale. Ha estado guay veros.
-Please stay. -We should get...
-Siéntate. -Deberíamos...
Can I see you out?
Te acompaño fuera.
I'll get my coat. Jack.
Voy a por mi abrigo. Jack.
Let me clarify.
Quiero dejar algo claro.
Yeah.
Sí.
She is not a superhero.
No es una superheroína.
Oh, yeah. Come on, I already knew that.
Ya, lo sé de sobra.
She's pretty good at all this, but...
Es bastante buena, pero...
Natasha Romanoff was pretty damn good at it, wasn't she?
Natasha Romanoff también era bastante buena, ¿no?
Being good isn't always enough to keep you alive.
Ser buena no siempre basta para seguir con vida.
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
I see.
Lo entiendo.
-Clint? -Yeah?
-¿Clint? -¿Sí?
Do you have kids?
¿Tienes hijos?
Yeah, I'm gonna assume that you do.
Vale, voy a suponer que sí.
It's been a rough week for my family.
Ha sido una semana dura para mi familia.
But I am letting you know that I cannot lose Kate.
Pero quiero que sepas que no puedo perder a Kate.
I've lost people before. I know in your line of work, you have, too.
Ya he perdido a varias personas. Y sé que, por tu profesión, tú también.
I understand. Okay.
Lo entiendo. Adiós.
So, you'll forget this case?
Entonces, ¿vais a dejar el caso?
I can't do that.
No puedo.
But what I can do is ensure that your daughter stays safe. Okay?
Pero puedo asegurarme de que tu hija esté a salvo, ¿vale?
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
(SIGHS)
Averigua lo que puedas sobre Sloan LTD.
(LINE RINGING)
(LINE BEEPS)
It's Eleanor. Um...
Soy Eleanor.
Could you call me back, please? It's urgent.
Llámame cuando puedas, por favor. Es urgente.
Hey. Did you find anything?
Hola. ¿Has encontrado algo?
I talked to that friend of yours. He's really busy.
He hablado con tu amigo. Está muy liado.
He's been learning Russian and jogging a ton.
Ha estado aprendiendo ruso y corriendo mogollón.
Tracksuits. So Sloan is their front?
Los Chándal. ¿Sloan es una tapadera?
Yep. He said that his boss, Jack Duquesne, never gives him a day off.
Sí. Dice que su jefe, Jack Duquesne, no le da ni un día libre.
Jack's CEO? He's laundering money for the big guy?
¿Jack es el director ejecutivo? ¿Blanquea dinero para el de arriba?
Let me guess, you're gonna need another day.
A ver si adivino, te quedas un día más.
Yeah, look, uh, this kid I'm helping is stuck in the middle of it,
Sí, la cría a la que estoy ayudando está metida en este berenjenal,
so I can't leave until I know she's safe.
no puedo irme sin saber que está a salvo.
I've been wondering...
Por cierto.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
¿Desapareció algo más de la base?
BARTON: You mean the Rolex?
¿Te refieres al Rolex?
Sí.
It's Dad.
Es papá.
I don't think... I don't think so.
No sé. No creo.
Why? Wasn't that destroyed, like, years ago?
¿Por qué? Creía que lo habían destruido hace años.
Well, I thought so, but I thought the same thing about your fancy outfit.
Bueno, eso creía yo, pero lo mismo pensaba de tu traje.
It's worth lookin' into, ain't it?
Deberíamos comprobarlo, ¿no?
If you can, check the signal from the transmitter.
Si puedes, comprueba la señal del transmisor.
Okay. You sound like you've been runnin' around all day. Are you tired?
Parece que no has parado en todo el día, ¿estás cansado?
Yeah, I'm a little banged up, but nothing's broken.
Sí, me han dado por todos lados, pero no me he roto nada.
Okay. Well, put your feet up.
Vale. Pues relájate un poco.
Ice them if you have to. Okay? I love you.
Y ponte hielo si hace falta, ¿vale? Te quiero.
I... I miss you.
Te echo de menos.
I'll see you soon. I promise.
Nos vemos pronto. Lo prometo.
Bye.
Adiós.
Uh, guys, looks like Dad's gonna be stuck at work a little longer.
Chicos, parece que papá tiene que quedarse allí un poco más.
(NATHANIEL GROANS)
ELEANOR: Obsessed. Completely obsessed with Clint Barton since...
Obsesionada. Totalmente obsesionada con Clint Barton desde...
Well, ever since the attack.
Desde el ataque.
JACK: She's awfully composed around her own idol.
Para ser su ídolo, no la pone nada nerviosa.
If I ever met Huey Lewis, I'd be a wreck.
Si yo conociera a Huey Lewis, me daría algo.
ELEANOR: Kate's always been confident,
Kate siempre ha sido muy segura.
never had to worry about her on that front.
Nunca me ha preocupado en ese sentido.
You're getting that pre-headache look, darling. Let me get you some tea.
Se te está poniendo cara de dolor de cabeza. Voy a hacerte un té.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY) Would you like something, Kate?
¿Tú quieres algo, Kate?
No. Thanks.
No. Gracias.
Mom, I really need to talk to you about Jack.
Mamá, tenemos que hablar de Jack.
Hey, could we... Um... Could we change the subject?
Oye, ¿podemos cambiar de tema?
You need to give him a break. Come on.
Dame un respiro, por Dios.
I... I need your help with a few decisions on the Bishop holiday party.
Necesito consejo para la fiesta de Navidad de la empresa.
I don't... I don't think I'm in the mood.
No sé... No estoy de humor.
Come on, Kate. You're great at this sort of thing.
Venga, Kate. Se te dan genial estas cosas.
The party's non-denominational,
Es una fiesta aconfesional,
encourages company camaraderie with a festive spirit.
fomenta el compañerismo con un ambiente festivo.
Sounds like a blast already.
La cosa promete.
Did someone say parties?
¿Alguien ha dicho "fiesta"?
Just make sure there's plenty of dancing.
Espero que el baile esté asegurado.
Well, my mother doesn't dance.
Mi madre no baila.
Oh, really? I beg to differ. Darling?
¿En serio? Discrepo. ¿Cariño?
(ELEANOR CHUCKLES)
(SINGING) Chestnuts roasting on an open fire
Castañas asándose en el fuego
Jack Frost nippin' at your ear
El invierno helando tu oreja
(JACK CHUCKLES)
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
And though it's been said many times, many ways
Y aunque ya te lo han dicho mil veces
Merry Christmas to you (ELEANOR CHUCKLES)
Te deseo feliz Navidad
Don't think I've ever seen you like that before.
Creo que nunca te había visto así.
(CHUCKLING) Wow!
A superhero house call and a serenade, all in one day.
Me visita un superhéroe y me dan una serenata, todo en el mismo día.
Well, you know what they say... life is short.
Bueno, ya sabes lo que dicen. La vida es muy corta.
You never know what you're gonna get.
Nunca sabes lo que te va a tocar.
(BOTH LAUGH)
What? What'd I say? Did I say something wrong or...
¿Qué? ¿Qué he dicho? ¿He dicho algo malo o...?
Every time you use one of those aphorisms, they are... wrong.
Siempre que usas algún aforismo así, lo usas... mal.
What? No. That can't be right, is it? Darling. Please. (CHUCKLING)
¿Qué? No. No es verdad, ¿a que no? Cariño, por favor.
The other day, you said, "Absence makes the heart grow older."
El otro día dijiste: "No sabes lo que tienes hasta que lo obtienes".
-(CHUCKLES) -Because that's what it does.
Porque es así.
-(CHUCKLING) Yeah. Honey. Come here. -No. Really?
-Cariño. Ven aquí. -¿O no?
Aw. You're making my heart grow older.
Yo sí que sé lo que tengo.
(JACK CHUCKLING)
I guess getting laughed at by family
Supongo que es mejor que tu familia se burle de ti
is better than being alone in the holidays, right?
que pasar las Navidades solo, ¿no?
ELEANOR: What's better than being with family? I'm so glad you're both here.
No hay nada mejor que estar en familia. Me alegro de que estéis aquí.
JACK: You know, we should play a board game. ELEANOR: That's a cute idea.
Podríamos jugar a un juego de mesa.
Buena idea.
JACK: Risk, Yahtzee, Stratego.
¿Risk, Yahtzee, Stratego?
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
(BUZZING)
KATE: It's me. I come bearing pizza and holiday cheer. Let me in.
Soy yo. Vengo cargada de pizza y espíritu navideño. Ábreme.
Mmm.
(DOOR BUZZES)
Come on, Pizza Do... Okay.
Venga, Perropizza. Vale.
(CHRISTMAS SONG PLAYING)
-Hey! -Hey.
-¡Hola! -Hola.
-A little help? -Hey, get outta there.
-¿Me ayudas? -Oye, deja eso.
All right, this is the classic Hawkeye costume we've been waitin' for. What is all this?
Vale. Ese es el traje de Ojo de Halcón que buscábamos.
This is me saving the holidays.
¿Qué es eso?
Is that right?
Lo que va a salvar las Navidades.
I'll get you home in time for the big day.
No me digas.
Estarás en casa para el día de Navidad.
Figured in the meantime, we could celebrate.
Pero mientras tanto, podemos celebrarla.
It's movie marathon night, right? Check this out. I got movies.
Hoy tocaba maratón de pelis, ¿no? Mira. Traigo varias.
That's very thoughtful of you.
Qué detalle.
Thanks.
Gracias.
But yeah, can we put a pause on that and talk about Sword Boy for a minute?
Pero ¿podemos hacer un paréntesis y hablar de don Espaditas un momento?
-You got good instincts, kid. -What do you mean?
-Tienes buen instinto. -¿A qué te refieres?
So, I did a little digging and turns out,
He estado investigando un poco, y resulta
Sloan's a shell company that launders money for the Tracksuits.
que Sloan es una empresa fantasma que blanquea para los Chándal.
And Jack Duquesne is the CEO.
Y Jack Duquesne es el director ejecutivo.
You sure?
¿Estás seguro?
Mmm.
Okay, well, we're just gonna have to come up with a plan to take down my mom's fiancé's organized crime ring
Vale, pues tendremos que pensar un plan para desmantelar
while simultaneously having a heartwarming holiday celebration.
la red criminal del novio de mi madre
mientras celebramos estas fechas tan entrañables.
(CHRISTMAS MUSIC PLAYING)
Got any more of that slushy stuff? -BARTON: In the kitchen. -Okay.
¿Hay más bolsitas para daiquiris?
-En la cocina. -Vale.
Okay, cops. We need to get the cops off my back. TSM, we need to get them to leave us alone.
Vale, la poli. Tenemos que quitármela de encima.
Los Chándal. Hay que conseguir que nos dejen en paz.
And we need to figure out why and how Jack is connected to it all.
Y hay que descubrir por qué y cómo está Jack metido en todo esto.
Yeah, right.
Sí, vale.
This the part where you finish my sentence with a plan. Planning's not really my thing. Are you sure that's dry erase?
Y esta es la parte donde tú acabas mi frase con un plan.
Los planes no son lo mío. ¿Seguro que no es permanente?
(CHRISTMAS SONG PLAYING)
Good boy.
Buen chico.
(CHRISTMAS SONG CONTINUES PLAYING)
How do we get more trick arrows?
¿Cómo conseguimos flechas truco?
Well, there are no more trick arrows.
Ya no hay más.
Like in the world?
¿En todo el mundo?
Basically. I have a few more trick arrowheads.
Exacto. Me quedan algunas puntas de flecha truco.
But you can't just put 'em on any shaft.
Pero no valen en cualquier asta.
So, we really have to get these back.
Habrá que recuperarlas.
What're you doing?
¿Qué haces?
See? Tree covers the parts that won't come off.
¿Has visto? El árbol tapa las partes que no se borran.
Well, now you're problem-solving.
Qué resolutiva.
-Have you ever heard of boomerang arrows? -What?
-¿Qué tal flechas bumerán? -¿Qué?
Why would I ever want to use a boomerang arrow?
¿Por qué iba a querer usar flechas bumerán?
-Because they come back. -Exactly.
-Porque siempre vuelven. -Exacto.
Yeah, well, if all trick arrows were boomerangs, then we'd have them all.
Pues eso, si las flechas truco fueran bumeranes, ahora las tendríamos.
Coming back at us.
Clavadas en el cuerpo.
You'd have to... You'd have to dodge.
Habría... que esquivarlas.
(CHUCKLES)
BARTON: No, it's not impossible.
No, no es imposible.
The first arrow you release just has to be wood.
Primero lanzas una flecha de madera,
So when you release the second one, it splits it up the middle.
así la partes por la mitad con la segunda.
-I call bullshit. I've tried it. -Well, I've done it a few times.
-Tú flipas. Ya lo he intentado. -Lo he hecho varias veces.
You got any other cool tricks?
¿Algún otro truco molón?
Well, I can knock somebody unconscious with that, like, 20 feet away.
Bueno, puedo tumbar con esto a alguien que esté a seis metros de mí.
No, you can't.
Qué dices.
I'd use a quarter or a nickel. A dime's too light.
Con una moneda de cinco centavos o así, las de diez no valen.
Prove it.
Demuéstralo.
What, knock you unconscious? No, I want you to hit something.
¿Quieres que te tumbe?
No, que le des a algo.
Fine, live forever without me believing you. I'll just tell every stranger that I see that Hawkeye is full of bullshit.
Vale, pues no me lo trago.
-(COIN CLATTERS) -(TV POWERS OFF)
Voy a decirle a todo el mundo que Ojo de Halcón es un fantasma.
Whoa!
(DOG WHINES)
You've got to show me how you did that.
Tienes que enseñarme a hacer eso.
(CHRISTMAS SONG PLAYING)
All right, you ready? Yeah.
Vale, ¿lista?
Sí.
You have a nice snap. Make sure you get that curve. Just a little one. Right, you got it, right?
El chasquido está bien. Te falta darle efecto.
Solo un poco. Lo pillas, ¿no?
(COIN CLATTERS)
BARTON: Oh, God.
Ay, madre.
(LAUGHS)
What are you doing? Ring finger.
¿Cómo lo coges?
Con este dedo.
-Grip it tight. -Yeah.
-Más fuerte. -Sí.
That was better.
Mucho mejor.
You can do it this time.
Esta es la buena.
Okay. (CLEARS THROAT)
Vale.
(TV POWERS ON)
-KATE: Oh, my God! -What?
-¡Toma ya! -¿Qué?
-Holy shit, I did it. -Yes.
-Tío, lo he conseguido. -Sí.
That was crazy.
Qué pasada.
Hey, not bad, kid.
No está mal.
Not bad. All right. Best shot you ever took?
Nada mal. Vale. ¿Cuál ha sido tu mejor disparo?
-Uh, the one I didn't take. -What does that mean?
-El que no disparé. -¿Qué significa eso?
Uh, it means... Never mind, shouldn't have said it.
Pues... Déjalo, no debería haber dicho nada.
-Oh, come on, you can't do that. -Never mind, it's nothin'.
-Venga, eso no se hace. -No es nada.
What? Come on, consider it my Christmas present. -No, it's not the right time. -Yes.
Venga. Es lo que quiero de regalo de Navidad.
-Look, it'll be a good story, I'm sure... -It's just not a good story, okay?
-No es el... -Sí.
-Seguro que la historia mola... -No mola, ¿vale?
It's...
Fue...
about the time I met someone.
...cuando la conocí.
I was sent to take her out.
Mi misión era liquidarla.
And when I got there, when it was time...
Y cuando llegué allí, cuando llegó el momento...
Um...
I couldn't do it.
...no pude hacerlo.
I just had this feeling that she wanted out.
Sentí que ella misma quería acabar con todo.
Turns out, I was right.
Y no me equivocaba.
KATE: You mean Natasha.
Hablas de Natasha.
Yeah.
Sí.
She was the best there was.
Era la mejor.
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
It's all right. It's, uh... When you do what I do for a living, it...
Tranquila. Cuando te dedicas a algo así...
It's just a game of managing loss, right? So...
...aprendes a perder a gente, ¿sabes?
(BARTON SIGHS)
Kids, Janie, Janie, Tommy!
¡Niños, Janie, Janie, Tommy!
MAN: (ON TV) Look at you. Oh, I could eat you up.
Madre mía. Estáis para comeros.
-Where's your mother? -BOY: She went looking for you.
-¿Y vuestra madre? -Ha ido a buscarte.
You lost your family in the Blip?
¿Perdiste a tu familia en el Lapso?
Yeah. Like half the world.
Sí. Como casi todo el mundo.
God, that must have been devastating.
Dios, debió de ser muy duro.
Yeah, there are no words.
No puedo ni describirlo.
Is that where you met the Ronin?
¿Ahí fue cuando conociste a Ronin?
(SIGHS)
It's you, isn't it?
Eres tú, ¿verdad?
Everybody dealt with the Blip in their own way.
Cada uno llevó el Lapso como pudo.
I continued doing what I was trained to do.
Yo seguí haciendo lo que me enseñaron a hacer.
Protect people.
Proteger a la gente.
Hurting people. Investigating first,
Hacerle daño. Siempre investigaba antes,
but in the end, my job has always been to hurt people.
pero, al final, mi trabajo consistía en hacerle daño a la gente.
You were a hero.
Eras un héroe.
I was a weapon.
Era un arma.
I was aimed by the right people at the right targets, so...
En manos de ciertas personas que apuntaban a ciertos objetivos.
Look, you made mistakes, but those are behind you.
Cometiste errores, pero ya los has dejado atrás.
No, it's tied to me.
No, viven conmigo.
Tied to my family.
Con mi familia.
That's why I'm here. And I can't go home till I fix it.
Por eso estoy aquí. No puedo volver a casa hasta que arregle esto.
I really appreciate what you did tonight.
Te agradezco lo de esta noche.
It means a lot.
De verdad.
You know, you should get some rest. You got a big day tomorrow.
Deberías irte a descansar. Mañana será un día movidito.
-Yes, boss. Good night. -'Night.
Claro, jefe. Buenas noches.
(CLICKING TONGUE) Come on!
-Buenas noches. -Vamos.
(INHALES)
(EXHALES)
How about now? (CHUCKLES)
¿Qué tal ahora?
NATASHA: Killing all these people isn't gonna bring your family back.
Matar a toda esa gente no te devolverá a tu familia.
It's okay.
Tranquilo.
Please.
Por favor.
(NATASHA GRUNTS) No!
¡No!
WOMAN: (OVER RADIO) It's three days until Christmas
Faltan tres días para Navidad,
and we've got your soundtrack for the holiday season. You're listening to New York's 107.6, light FM.
y os traemos la banda sonora para las fiestas.
Sintonizas WLTW, 107.9, Nueva York, Light FM.
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
-Morning. -Mornin'.
-Buenos días. -Buenos días.
-Some coffee. -Oh, thank God.
-He hecho café. -Menos mal.
Okay, this morning, I'm gonna have a talk with our friend, Kazi.
Voy a charlar con nuestro colega Kazi esta mañana.
What I want you to do is track down the trick arrows
Y necesito que tú vayas a por las flechas truco que tienen
from our friends, the LARPers.
nuestros amigos los Larpers.
(CHUCKLES)
-Wait, what? -My tracer arrow stopped moving,
-Espera, ¿qué? -Las flechas llevan un localizador.
and it's over by an NYPD facility down by the bridge.
Se ha parado en unas instalaciones de la Policía.
And now the LARPers, they're mostly first responders, one's a cop.
Muchos Larpers son de los servicios de emergencias, hay polis.
See if they can get access to that NYPD facility. LARPer friends.
Descubre si pueden acceder a esas instalaciones.
Los Larpers.
Yeah, they're... They're colorful. You're gonna love 'em.
Sí, son personajes interesantes. Verás qué bien te caen.
You know, I like to think of them more as our arrows.
Oye, me gustaría que las llamáramos "nuestras flechas".
Okay. Go get our arrows.
Vale, ve a por nuestras flechas.
Hmm.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
WOMAN: Thrust!
¡Propulsión!
MAN: Lightning Bolt! One, two, three, four, five.
¡Flecha rayo! Un, dos, tres, cuatro, cinco.
WOMAN: Retreat! Formation. Stab!
¡Retirada! Formación. ¡Atacad!
(SHOUTS)
Ice Wall!
¡Muro de hielo!
(WOMAN YELLS INDISTINCTLY)
Superpower Doom! (ALL YELLING)
¡Muerte fatal!
Hey, I, uh... I don't mean to interrupt... (ALL YELLING)
Hola. No es por interrumpir...
-Wow. You guys are... -WOMAN: Retreat!
-Se os ve muy... -¡Retirada!
Dedicated. Who are you?
...entregados.
¿Quién eres tú?
Uh, Hawkeye sent me here on official Avengers business.
Me envía Ojo de Halcón por un asunto oficial de Vengadores.
I'm his partner-slash-best-friend, Kate.
Soy su socia/mejor amiga, Kate.
He said you guys could help us out. One of you is a cop?
Ha dicho que podríais ayudarnos. ¿Algún poli?
That's me, Officer Wendy Conrad. Better as Els-Bath of Deepdale.
Yo, agente Wendy Conrad. Más conocida como Els-Bath de Deepdale.
Officer. Basically, all we need is some
Agente. En resumidas cuentas, necesitamos
casual, run-of-the-mill evidence tampering.
manipular unas pruebas de nada.
Hawkeye's trick arrows are in an NYPD facility near the Manhattan Bridge.
Las flechas truco han acabado en la instalación policial de Manhattan.
I can probably help you out
-Podría ayudaros. -Genial.
if you make it worth my while.
Si me compensara.
Worth our while.
Si nos compensara.
Yeah. Yeah, sure, totally. Whatever you want. All right.
Sí, claro. Lo que queráis. Vale.
All in? Okay. This is gonna be great.
-Muy bien. -¿Os apuntáis todos? Qué bien.
You guys are awesome, outfits, the... It's just really awesome.
Tíos, sois lo más. Los trajes, los... Me flipa todo.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Surprise. Ah, ah. Just wanna talk.
Sorpresa. Solo quiero hablar.
I need to get out of the city.
Tengo que irme de la ciudad.
But before I go, I need to put this Ronin situation to bed.
Pero antes de hacerlo, quiero zanjar el asunto de Ronin.
Look, I know you have Maya's ear,
Mira, sé que Maya te escucha,
and you seem like you're a reasonably not stupid guy.
y no tienes pinta de ser muy tonto.
If you're tryin' to flatter me, you are way off the mark.
Si intentas halagarme, vas muy mal encaminado.
Don't get me wrong, I think you're a doormat.
Qué va, me pareces un perrito faldero.
Look, you've been working under William Lopez as a lieutenant for, what, for four years?
Has sido teniente
bajo las órdenes de William Lopez durante cuatro años.
And now under Maya for a few more years.
Y ahora trabajas bajo las órdenes de Maya.
You know this operation better than anybody.
Conoces esta operación mejor que nadie.
You know what Maya's boss wants.
Sabes lo que quiere el jefe de Maya.
And you know what he's already done to get it.
Y has visto lo que es capaz de hacer.
So what do you know?
Qué sabrás tú.
I know he doesn't like this attention, that's for sure.
Que no le gusta llamar tanto la atención, eso seguro.
I know Maya's obsession, wanting to hunt Ronin down, is dangerous.
Sé que la obsesión de Maya por dar caza a Ronin es peligrosa.
Clouds her judgment, don't you think?
Le nubla la razón, ¿no crees?
So you're concerned for the organization? And, uh... And my rank in it?
O sea, ¿te preocupa la organización y mi rango en ella?
What do you want?
¿Qué quieres?
I don't want anybody else to die.
Que no muera nadie más.
But Maya's need for vengeance is gonna get her killed.
Pero la sed de venganza de Maya acabará con ella.
Period.
Es así.
Looking for this? Or maybe it's the box cutter under the seat.
¿Buscas esto? ¿O el cúter de debajo del asiento?
Look, are we done here?
Oye, ¿has acabado ya?
She's chasing a ghost.
Persigue a un fantasma.
I think you know that. But I can't convince her of that.
Y lo sabes. Pero a mí no me escuchará.
And I'm guessing you're the only one who can.
Me parece que solo te escuchará a ti.
This is the final warning. Just get it done.
Último aviso. Hazlo.
Hey, can I have my gun back?
Oye, ¿me devuelves la pistola?
Yeah, what do you think?
Claro. ¿A ti qué te parece?
(DOOR CLOSES)
Ah, come on.
Venga ya.
(CHRISTMAS SONG PLAYING)
-There's our guy. -Hey.
-Ya está aquí. -Hola.
Snickerdoodle? They're still warm.
¿Una galleta? Siguen calentitas.
-Okay. -Hey, come on in.
-Vale. -Venga, pasa.
-Hey, Clint. How'd your day go? -Hi.
-Hola, Clint. ¿Cómo ha ido el día? -Hola.
My, uh... My day's been fine. How are you doing?
Bastante bien. ¿Qué tal el tuyo?
Great, yeah. Better than yours, I'd say.
Genial, sí. Creo que mejor que el tuyo.
So did you, uh, get my gear?
¿Has encontrado mis cosas?
Yeah, yeah. They're on the way.
Sí. Están de camino.
They should be here any minute. Yeah, relax.
Estarán al caer. Tranquilo.
-What? -Check that out.
-¿Qué? -Mira.
(KATE CHUCKLES)
Not gonna lie, I look pretty good as a Viking.
La verdad, el rollo vikingo me queda de muerte.
-I... You know, I made this myself. -No way!
-Lo he hecho yo. -¿Cómo flipas?
-By hand. -Could I hire you to make my next one?
-A mano. -Podrías hacerme un traje.
Oh, yeah. I would love to.
Claro. Me encantaría.
Hey, wait a second. What if that's our deal?
A ver, un momento. Ese podría ser el trato.
-What deal? -We get you the arrows and info,
-¿Qué trato? -Las flechas y la información
and you get us materials for a new costume.
a cambio de material para hacer trajes nuevos.
Okay, how about enough materials to make your costumes plus two more?
Vale, ¿y si os conseguimos material para vuestros trajes y dos trajes más?
I know a certain someone who needs a little help with theirs.
Sé de uno al que no le vendría mal una ayudita.
-I'm in. -Great!
-Hecho. -¡Guay!
Hey, Orval, you hear that? We gettin' new costumes.
Oye, Orval, ¿has oído? Vamos a tener trajes nuevos.
Uh, Kate, I asked you to simply retrieve my arrows, not stage a play.
Te he pedido que recuperaras mis flechas, no que montaras una película.
Uh, we're a... We're a guild.
Somos un gremio.
(PHONE BUZZING)
Laura: No destruyeron el Rolex.
Está en el 3715 de Godfrey Road.
Okay. I gotta go.
Vale. Tengo que irme.
We gotta go. We're in this together, right?
Dirás "tenemos". Estamos juntos en esto, ¿no?
-Excuse me, sorry. -You're gonna have to change. -Hawkeye. -Oh, hi.
-Perdón. -Tendrás que cambiarte.
-Ojo de Halcón. -Hola.
Arrow Retrieval Mission complete.
Misión Rescate de Flechas completada.
Oh, yes. Thank you so much. Appreciate it.
Anda, muchísimas gracias. Te lo agradezco.
This is my bag.
La bolsa es mía.
-Okay. -You didn't bring your own bag?
-Vale. -¿No habéis traído bolsa?
No, I mean...
No, o sea...
My wife gave me this bag. It's embroidered. It says "Bombshell."
Me la regaló mi mujer. La bordó ella. Pone "pibonazo".
I... I can see that, that it's very important to you.
Ya lo veo, y entiendo que sea importante para ti.
He'll get it back to you. Yeah, I'll make sure of it.
Te la devolverá. Ya me aseguraré yo.
-Right? -I promise.
-¿Vale? -Te lo prometo.
-Let's go. -Right. Okay.
-Vamos. -Sí, vale.
-Thank you. See ya. -Okay then.
-Gracias. Adiós. -Vale.
-Thank you so much. -Beautiful bag.
-Muchas gracias. -Una bolsa preciosa.
Thank you.
-Muy bonita. -Adiós.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
KATE: You wanna tell me what we're doing here?
¿Se puede saber qué hacemos aquí?
BARTON: Something very important to me is pinging inside that apartment.
Hay un objeto muy importante para mí dentro de ese piso.
It was stolen from a black market auction. I need it back.
Lo robaron en la subasta. Tengo que recuperarlo.
No lights, no movement.
Ni luz... ni movimiento.
(KATE SIGHS)
This is our chance.
Es nuestra oportunidad.
This would have been easier if we were on a higher rooftop.
Hubiera sido más fácil desde una azotea más alta.
That's what you think.
Esa es tu opinión.
Yeah, exactly. That's why I said it.
Sí, exacto. Por eso lo he dicho.
Kate, you always wanna prioritize a quick exit over a quick entrance
Kate, siempre hay que priorizar una salida rápida a una entrada rápida.
so when things go sideways, and they usually do,
Así, si las cosas se tuercen, cosa que suele pasar,
you have an exit strategy. That's why I chose this spot.
tienes una estrategia de escape. De ahí que haya elegido esta azotea.
It's got good sightlines for all my exits.
Hay un buen campo visual de todas las salidas.
Entry should be easy. Think it should take me about three and a half minutes to get in.
Entrar debería ser fácil. Debería costarme
unos tres minutos y medio entrar.
So, if you see anything out here, just give me a signal, Kate. All right?
Si ves algo desde aquí, me avisas, ¿vale?
Kate?
¿Kate?
-(CAR HONKING) -MAN: What're you doin?
¿Qué haces?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Kate? Kate?
¿Kate?
-There you are. -I told you you're supposed to be lookout.
-Por fin. -Se suponía que ibas a vigilar tú.
Yeah, but of the two of us, who do you trust up there not to get distracted? That's not fair, that your inability
Ya, pero de los dos, ¿quién crees que se distraerá menos ahí arriba?
No es justo que por tu incapacidad
to act like a grown-up helps you get your way.
de comportarte como una adulta, consigas salirte con la tuya.
(SCOFFS) No, it's not. But it is what it is.
No, no es justo. Pero es lo que hay.
I need you to use your grappling hook arrow to anchor yourself in.
Usa una flecha gancho para sujetarte.
Propel down the side of the building to the window.
Baja por un lado hasta llegar a la ventana.
If it's locked, break in quietly.
Si está cerrada, ábrela sin hacer ruido.
Yeah, love all of that. Great plan, just a slight tweak though.
Sí, me encanta. Un plan genial. Pero voy a cambiarlo un poco.
Good evening, sir. Can I help you with your bags? -Oh. Thank you. -(CHUCKLES) Sure.
Buenas noches. ¿Lo ayudo con las bolsas?
What are you... No, no, no.
-Gracias. -De nada.
¿Qué...? No.
BARTON: No, no, no. Don't... Don't engage.
No. No hables con él.
-Got celery, a little Kashi. -BARTON: Kate.
-Apio, cereales... -Kate.
Okay, some pretzels?
Anda, y lacitos.
Where are you?
¿Dónde estás?
-(DINGS) -Oh, relax. I'm taking the elevator.
Tranqui. Estoy en el ascensor.
I'm sorry, what was that?
Perdona, ¿has dicho algo?
Oh, I, uh... I'm sorry, I wasn't talking to you. (CHUCKLES)
Perdone, no hablaba con usted.
Can I tell you a secret?
¿Le cuento un secreto?
BARTON: Please don't do this. I was talking to an Avenger.
No, por favor.
Hablaba con un vengador.
He's in my ear. BARTON: Maybe you should stop talking.
Llevo un pinganillo.
Igual deberías callarte.
Yeah, I'm his partner.
Sí, soy su socia.
I'll just take this back.
Ya cojo yo las bolsas.
I can help you to the door, no problem.
Lo acompaño a la puerta, tranquilo.
No, that's all right. I got it from here.
No, déjalo. Puedo solo.
Okay, are you sure? It's really no problem.
¿Está seguro? No es molestia.
All right, you take care now.
Vale, cuídese.
-(ELEVATOR DINGS) -(GROANS)
What do you do with this giant bow problem?
¿Tú te paseas con el arco por ahí?
I have a collapsible one.
Tengo uno plegable.
Oh, that makes sense.
Tiene sentido.
Okay. I'm at the door.
Vale. Estoy en la puerta.
We're good.
Todo despejado.
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
Okay. Living room's all clear.
Vale. Salón despejado.
Oh, shit.
Mierda.
(ARROW WHOOSHES)
(ARROW WHOOSHING)
What was that?
¿Qué ha sido eso?
I don't know. There are, like, strobe lights attached to the wall. -BARTON: What do you mean, strobe lights? -I don't know.
No sé. Hay luces estroboscópicas en las paredes.
-¿Cómo que luces estroboscópicas? -No sé.
Yeah, what do you see?
Bueno, ¿qué ves?
Okay, what am I lookin' for?
Vale, ¿qué estoy buscando?
A watch, vintage Rolex.
Un reloj, un Rolex clásico.
Belongs to someone I used to work with.
Era de alguien con quien trabajaba.
Is that the whole story, Clint?
¿No vas a contarme más, Clint?
BARTON: They've been out of the game a long time,
Lleva mucho tiempo fuera de juego,
but their identity is still attached to that watch.
pero su identidad sigue ligada a ese reloj.
Hmm. And if the Tracksuits find out about it?
¿Y si lo descubren los Chándal?
It would blow their cover. Goodbye, friend.
Arruinaría su tapadera. Acabarían con él.
Got the watch.
Tengo el reloj.
Great.
Genial.
Hang on a minute.
Un momento.
Clint, somebody is taking notes on your family.
Clint, aquí hay notas sobre tu familia.
BARTON: What?
¿Qué?
"Clint Barton, wife, Laura, daughter, Lila, age 14,
"Clint Barton. Mujer: Laura. Hija: Lila, 14 años.
"son, Cooper, age 16, son, Nate." What...
"Hijo: Cooper, 16 años. Hijo: Nate". ¿Qué...?
Kate, get out of there now.
Kate, sal de ahí ahora mismo.
What? Why?
¿Qué? ¿Por qué?
That light's an alarm. It's a silent alarm for people that can't hear.
Las luces eran una alarma. Una alarma silenciosa, no se oye.
Oh, my God.
Dios.
It's Maya's apartment.
Es el piso de Maya.
BARTON: All right, I'm coming...
Voy para allá.
(BARTON GRUNTING)
Clint, what's going on?
Clint, ¿qué pasa?
Clint? (BARTON GROANING)
¿Clint?
(GRUNTS, GROANS)
Maya's here.
Maya está aquí.
BARTON: Yeah, I can see that.
Sí, ya lo veo.
Then why didn't you tell me?
¿Y por qué no me lo has dicho?
BARTON: I did. Maya's on the roof with me.
Te lo he dicho. Está en la azotea conmigo.
-No, Maya is definitely here. -(GLASS BREAKING)
No, Maya está aquí.
(GRUNTING)
Well, who the hell am I fighting then?
¿Y con quién narices estoy peleando yo?
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY) A little help?
¿Una ayudita?
(GROANING)
Give me a second. Incoming.
Dame un segundo. Marchando.
Get on the zip line.
Tírate por la tirolina.
(GASPS)
(BARTON GRUNTING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(EXHALES)
(BARTON GRUNTING)
Oh, this is great. (BREATHING HEAVILY)
Qué bien.
-(GASPS) -(ZIPLINE CREAKS)
(GRUNTS) Come on. Come on.
Venga.
(GRUNTS)
(KATE GASPS)
(GROANS) That hurt.
Qué pupa.
(GUN COCKING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(YELLING)
No, no, no! No, no!
¡No!
(BREATH TREMBLING)
Pull me up!
¡Súbeme!
(BARTON BREATHING HEAVILY)
Get outta here.
Vete.
(GRUNTS)
(LIGHTS CLATTERING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
-(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING) -(GROANS)
(EXHALES)
(EXHALES SHARPLY) Who the hell was that?
¿Quién narices era esa?
You don't wanna know, Kate.
Es mejor que no lo sepas.
I cannot be your partner if you don't tell me what's going on.
No puedo ser tu socia si no me cuentas qué pasa.
You're not my partner. Do you understand that?
No eres mi socia, a ver si te entra en la cabeza.
You never were.
Nunca lo has sido.
Someone has hired a Black Widow assassin.
Alguien ha contratado a una viuda negra.
This has gotten very real, very quickly.
La cosa se ha puesto muy seria muy rápido.
So I'm doing this alone.
Así que haré esto solo.
No, you're not.
No, ni hablar.
Look, I know that tonight didn't go as planned, but I chose to be here.
Sé que hoy no ha ido como esperábamos, pero estoy aquí porque quiero.
I understand the risk, I understand all of that.
Entiendo los riesgos. Lo entiendo todo.
I'm not gonna do it.
No pienso hacerlo.
Do you hear me?
¿Me oyes?
(SNIFFLES)
Go home, Kate. It's over.
Vete a casa, Kate. Se acabó.
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL CHRISTMAS MUSIC PLAYING)
---oOo---
Basada en los cómics de Marvel
Marvel Studios presenta
Ojo de Halcón
---oOo---